CONGRATS ON NATIONALS
[Taiki] Nationals are over,
and we're nearing the end of summer break.
It's time we start worrying
about unfinished homework.
AUGUST 26
ASSIGNMENT
OFFENSE/DEFENSE
But on this day, August 26th...
[popping]
[exclaims]
[Nagisa] Hey, Chii!
[all] Happy Birthday, Chinatsu!
Thank you so much!
- [laughter]
- All right, here you go.
Let's put this on.
[girl] I have a present for you.
[Chinatsu] Ooh, what is it?
DEER
[Nagisa] A Chinatsu original deer,
now on a shirt!
- Wear it at practice.
- [gasps]
Say cheese, girls.
[all] Cheese!
[camera shutter clicks]
[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
- [laughter]
- Wow!
EPISODE 15
AUGUST 26
Nice one! Let me see.
Girls are into that kind of thing,
aren't they?
- [boy 2] It's a cuteness overload.
- [Nagisa] So funny.
It's her birthday, apparently.
I know that!
I've been gathering information
for weeks now.
Running comparisons of gifts,
making pros and cons.
What if I get her the same thing
as someone else, or do too much?
Picking out a birthday present isn't easy.
And then, well...
ever since nationals,
I feel like she's been a little down.
So I kind of figured
she didn't want a big celebration.
- [laughter]
- [Kyo] Mm?
[Nagisa] Let's celebrate!
However! I'll figure
something out by toni-- [grunts]
- [Hina] Oh.
- [Taiki] Huh?
My bad, sorry.
Hina! You are so doing that on purpose.
[Hina] Whoa, rude much!
As if I'm trying to find
an excuse to talk to you.
[gasps softly]
Hina, could you and I go talk for a sec?
Hm?
So what's up?
Wait, are you gonna do something weird?
Don't make jokes that are hard to follow!
I was only trying to lighten the mood.
So, Hina,
you said the other day,
that you don't need an answer yet, right?
Yeah.
But the thing is,
I do have feelings for Chinatsu...
so I would like
to give that a shot myself.
Would that be okay?
What? Yeah, for sure.
[gasps softly]
It's like I said,
I know how you feel about her,
so I can understand.
It'd be more annoying
if you held back because of me.
[Kyo] Of course it's not okay.
[basketball dribbling]
- [girl] Chinatsu!
- [panting]
What are you doing?
Defense is closing you in!
You've got the other side too!
Got it!
- He is really tough on Chii, huh?
- That's how it has to be.
All the upperclassmen are gone now.
It is hard on her, yeah,
but he wants her to be a player
who can make that winning shot.
[inaudible]
[girl] What did the coach say?
[Chinatsu] That, since Yoshitani retired,
I should keep up the hard work
and step up as vice-captain.
Yo, I knew it!
[girl] Our next captain's
gonna be Chinatsu!
[Tagawa] You've got the skills to do it,
and the younger players
really look up to you.
[Nagisa] Do you actually want to though?
Isn't leading not really your thing?
I was our class representative for a term!
'Cause you lost rock-paper-scissors.
I do feel like the pressure's on...
but I'd do anything for this team.
- Well said, well said!
- I'm behind you, Vice-Captain!
Very cool!
- [girls chattering indistinctly]
- [Chinatsu chuckling]
[basketball dribbling]
[teacher] Excuse me!
It's time for me to lock up!
Understood!
[phone vibrates]
MOM
Hello? Mom?
Chinatsu! Happy birthday!
Whoa, Mom, my ears
are ringing after that one.
My voice had to make it all the way
to Japan, can you blame me?
So, any news to report?
Nothing really.
Are you sure?
You don't sound completely like yourself.
The phone can do that
to your voice sometimes, but I'm okay.
Oh, that's what it is.
It's not that I have news...
Hm?
...but I got chosen as vice-captain.
That's amazing!
Coach and Kikuchi
really wanted me to take the role,
so I wanna give it my all, but...
I think I told you last time we talked...
I missed a shot at nationals
when it really mattered.
Even though I had practiced
the best I could,
I still missed it.
[moody music playing]
Honestly, I still have so much work to do
to improve myself as a player.
I don't know how I can focus
on the rest of team too.
I think I'm not ready for this, you know?
[sighs] Listen, Chinatsu.
It's not too late to think about that
after you've tried.
It's okay to give this a shot
and have it not go well.
If and when that happens,
rather than thinking
it didn't work because of you,
think about everything you learned
from the experience.
If there's anything you should be
keeping in mind going forward,
it's who you're going to rely on
when you're thinking that way.
[exclaims softly]
Being relied on by other people
can be a pretty nice feeling, you know.
All right. I should be going.
Yeah. Thanks.
MOM - NAGISA
YUKIKO INOMATA - KIKUCHI SENPAI
[sighs]
HEY, HEY
- [phone chimes]
- [Taiki grunts]
[Chinatsu gasps softly]
Huh?
[grunts nervously]
Wait! I swear I wasn't stalking you!
It's a coincidence.
But hang on... this sticker...
I didn't think she'd send me this again.
I wanna go somewhere.
[Taiki] Do you mind a train ride?
Just a bit longer, I promise.
Okay.
[gasps]
[uplifting music playing]
[exclaims]
[Chinatsu] The ocean!
Back in grade school,
I used to come here pretty often.
The sun's about to set,
so you can't swim, but...
[giggles]
[Taiki] There's that
childlike side of her.
[Chinatsu giggling]
[gasps softly]
[Taiki] I'm glad.
Seems like this cheered her up a bit.
Come on, Taiki, you gotta join me in here!
[Taiki] Just a second!
[Chinatsu] Hurry up, hurry up!
[exclaims] Chinatsu, your wish bracelet...
Yeah. I don't have it. It finally broke.
I guess we piled on
too many wishes after all.
That's too bad.
[Taiki] That's too bad.
We don't match anymore, do we?
[grunts]
What did you do that for?
You were just standing there,
all spaced out.
And again!
You'll pay for that!
[both chuckle]
[Taiki] Hold on! Wait!
- [Chinatsu] I'm going again!
- Agh! It's so cold!
Looky there. Didn't realize
young couples still did stuff like that.
They're shining as brightly
as the sun behind them.
Although, it looks like the weather's
about to take a turn for the worse.
Chinatsu, time out, hold on.
The sand around this area makes you sink.
- Is that even a thing here?
- I'm telling the truth!
- You gotta be careful.
- [Chinatsu exclaims]
[soft piano music playing]
- Thanks.
- [Taiki] No worries.
Huh?
I don't think
we want you falling in, right?
Oh... Right.
[grunts, yells in agony]
[Chinatsu] It's a good thing
you had your sweatpants with you.
[Taiki groans]
[Taiki] This outfit looks ridiculous!
Am I really riding the train like this?
Your other pants won't be dry in time.
Let's head back after the sun sets.
Thanks for bringing me, Taiki. It's great.
Chinatsu...
today is your birthday, right?
[Chinatsu] Mm-hm.
I actually have a present for you.
It's a small thing, but...
Cake?
You had this the whole time?
I asked them to give me
a lot of ice packs for it.
And I, of course, brought the candles.
I can't believe I'm 17 already.
Birthdays really do matter, huh?
You feel yourself
inching toward becoming an adult.
Your birthday is in January, right?
Yeah. It's on January 15th.
[Chinatsu] So, since you're 15 right now,
we're two years apart.
Being two years apart,
it isn't that big a deal.
You're right.
Until we're adults, we're still kids!
All right, and now for the singing!
- ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
- You're singing?
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear... ♪
♪ Chinatsu ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
[wind blowing]
Oh, the wind did it for me.
Should I relight them?
It's okay.
Let's eat.
- You know what? About the wish bracelet...
- Mm?
We'll be matching again
before you know it.
'Cause next year, mine's gonna come off.
Uh. [chuckles]
[Taiki] What are you laughing at?
[Chinatsu] Mm... It's nothing.
[Taiki] Ugh, why do I feel like
there is something?
[Chinatsu] It's just, I was thinking
how you can be randomly cheesy sometimes.
[Taiki] What?
[Taiki] C'mon, this way!
The rain came outta nowhere.
I got wet after all.
Mom's gonna give me an earful when we--
OUT OF SERVICE
DUE TO LANDSLIDE
[both] Huh?
OUT OF SERVICE
[Taiki groans]
[both] What?
GUESTHOUSE SIOMIHAMA
[Taiki] Yeah. I know, I'm sorry.
We were at the beach,
and there was a landslide.
Yeah. They only had one room open.
It's fine, my friends are here too.
Yeah. Sure thing.
Talk soon.
[sighs]
No, nothing about this is fine!
There's a landslide, so we can't go home,
there's only one room
at the inn we ran into,
I lied to my mom that my friends
are here with us...
and I'm staying in the same room
with Chinatsu all night!
I mean, I'm not gonna do anything weird.
Really, I'm more worried that she might be
disappointed that her birthday,
of all days, turned out like this.
Are you done on the phone?
[gasps softly]
What did Yukiko say?
Huh? Uh...
Well, she told us to be careful.
Ah.
[Taiki] Oh, man, I'm doomed!
There's no way
I'm getting any sleep tonight.
- Taiki.
- [grunts]
GAME OF LIVES
They had all of these in the lobby!
Let's play together!
Since we have to stay overnight,
we might as well
do a board game all-nighter!
What should we play?
I'm really good with whatever.
It's your birthday.
You're right. Today is my birthday.
[Taiki] She's fast.
- I can be the dealer.
- [phone vibrates]
NAGISA
[Chinatsu] Oh. Nagisa's calling me.
Sorry, do you mind?
No. Should I give you some space, then?
That's okay.
Oh.
[Chinatsu] Oh, it's a video call.
Huh?
A very happy birthday!
This is part two!
Thanks, Nagisa!
[Taiki] Wait. Did I need to hide?
Were you just calling
to celebrate with me again?
And there's also something
that I've been wanting to tell you.
Today or, more like recently,
it seems like you've been down
and not feeling yourself.
[Chinatsu sighs]
I know you're under pressure,
but I've got your back
and I'm here for you.
We'll keep getting better.
I know that we will.
Let's do this as a team.
[Chinatsu] Yeah. Thanks.
So that's what I wanted to say to you,
but you already seem more relaxed.
Huh?
You were kinda giving off
negative vibes at practice earlier.
Well, any bad mood
is bound to pass at some point!
Can't argue with that.
Wait a sec. I just noticed
you're wearing a yukata.
Like you wear at an inn...
[Chinatsu] Yeah. I'm staying
with my extended family.
It all makes sense now,
that's why you're more upbeat.
[chuckles] You were bummed
you couldn't wear a yukata
to the fireworks festival, remember?
That's not true, you're making that up.
Lies. I saw you eyeing
everybody wearing one!
[Chinatsu] You were, too, Nagisa.
[Taiki] I will say, I'm glad I got to see
Chinatsu wearing a yukata.
- All right, I'm gonna get going.
- See ya.
[grunts]
[exclaims]
NAGISA
CALL ENDED
Whoa, nice catch.
But she heard me yell.
Don't worry about it.
She had hung up the phone already.
Was that a man's voice just now?
Maybe her uncle?
Okay then, that's a relief.
- Nagisa really is a good friend.
- Isn't she?
All the people in my life are kind.
I'm lucky.
Actually,
I wanted to apologize
about the fireworks festival.
Huh?
When we talked about it at home,
I think I said
I was going with my friends.
But no one else we asked
was able to join us,
and then Kyo got a fever the day of...
so I didn't go in a group.
And it ended up looking
like I'd lied about it.
- [gasps softly]
- So I...
am sorry.
You don't have to make a big deal
about something like that, Taiki.
Well, okay, you might be right, but...
even so, I still wanted
to apologize for it.
[chuckles softly]
Okay then, I also have something
I want to apologize for.
Wait, what is it?
I want to take back what I said to you.
About it not being a good thing.
[gasps softly]
I drew a boundary between us,
and probably made you feel like
you had to keep your distance.
I think it was a bit harsh of me
to do that to you.
No, no, it wasn't...
[Taiki] I do understand
where she's coming from.
And so...
[sighs]
I hope that you can accept my apology.
You don't have to make
a big deal about it.
Huh?
I think we can call it even.
[chuckles softly]
All right, now let's play a game.
With two players, how 'bout Last Card?
- Oh, I haven't played that.
- Really?
[birds chirping]
[groans softly]
[snoring softly]
Why didn't he just sleep on the futon?
He's gonna be all sore.
[pleasant music playing]
Hm?
Hmm?
[grunts]
[chuckles]
[Chinatsu] Good morning...
17-year-old me.
[closing theme song playing]